Guide to the Lorenzo and Ruth Bennett Morgan Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Lorenzo and Ruth Bennett Morgan Papers
1862-2001
RG 126
Yale University Divinity School Library
22
(37 boxes; 8 oversize boxes)
Extensive correspondence, diaries, writings, collected material, and photographs document the medical mission work of Lorenzo and Ruth Bennett Morgan in Jiangsu and Anhui provinces as well as Lorenzo Morgan's internment in Shanghai during World War II. The work of mission hospitals, famine relief, plague treatment, mission politics, mission family life, and political events in China are documented. The Morgans were medical missionaries in China, serving under the Presbyterian and Methodist mission boards from 1905 to 1946.
Morgan, Lorenzo Seymour
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carrel and Dorothy Morgan, 2002 - 2005
Biographical / Historical
1875 Aug 15 Lorenzo Seymour Morgan, (also known as Loren) born near Galva, Henry County, IL, fifth in a family of eight children, the son of John Norris Morgan and Mary McKinny Morgan. His siblings were Blanche Juliana, Fannie, Norris, Willis, Jennie, Harold, and Meryl.
1877 Sep 20 Ruth Bennett born in Morton, Tazewell County, IL, second in a family of two children, daughter of William S. Bennett and Mary Ann Campbell Bennett. Her brother was Ralph Bennett.
1895 Jun LSM graduated from Galva High School
1895-1896 LSM taught for one year in the country school he attended
1900 Jun LSM graduated from Knox College, Galesburg, IL with a Bachelor of Science Degree
1900 Jun Ruth Bennett graduated from University of Illinois
1900 Oct LSM and RB began study at The Johns Hopkins Medical School, Baltimore, MD
1904 Jun 14 LSM and RB received their M.D. degrees from Johns Hopkins Medical School
1904 LSM and RB traveled to Nashville, TN, where they were appointed as missionaries of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S. (Southern Presbyterian church)
1904 Jun 29 Marriage of Lorenzo Morgan and Ruth Bennett in First Church, Nashville, TN
1904 Nov LSM and RBM set sail for China
1905 Jan 1 LSM and RBM arrived in the port of Shanghai, China
1905 After a few months learning Chinese in Chinkiang [Zhenjiang], they were called to join Dr. James Woods at the hospital in Tsingkiang Pu [Qingjiang], Kiang Su [Jiangsu] Province
1907 Major famine in North Kiang Su Province
1907 Apr 14 Death of infant son in Tsingkiang Pu
1908 Mar 10 Birth of daughter Ruth Pearce Morgan at Tsingkiang Pu Hospital
1908 Death of John Norris Morgan, father of Loren, in Galva, IL
1909 Work on the new Ellen Lavine Graham Hospital is begun in Haichow [Haizhou], Kiang Su [Jiangsu] Province and the Morgans are transferred there to help complete it
1911-1912 First furlough in the USA; studied medicine and surgery
1914 Jul 4 Birth of daughter Juliana Louise Morgan at the hospital in Tsingtao [Qingdao], Shantung [Shandong] Province
1915 Summer spent at missionary resort in Kuling
1916 Summer spent in Kuling
1917 Aug 25 Birth of son Carrel Bennett Morgan at Haichow, Kiang Su Province
1918 LSM involved in plague prevention in Tatung [Datong] in northeast China
1919-1921 Second furlough in the USA; studied childhood diseases
1922 Summer spent in Kuling; Ruth Pearce entered the Shanghai American School
1925-1926 Summers spent at the seashore near Haichow
1927 Spring Violent revolution broke out in Haichow
1927 Jun Ruth Pearce Morgan graduated from the Shanghai American School
1927-1928 Third furlough in the USA
1929 Cholera epidemic in Haichow
1929 Jun 15 Death of Mary Bennett, RBM's mother, in Los Angeles, CA, at the age of 93
1930 Death of Mary McKinny Morgan, mother of Loren, in Galva, IL
1932 LSM and RBM left Haichow for the Presbyterian Hospital in Chinkiang [Zhenjiang]
1934 Jun LSM and RBM transferred from the Presbyterian Mission Board to the Methodist Mission Board. They were assigned to the Methodist sponsored Wuhu General Hospital in "Ichisan," Wuhu, Anhwei [Anhui] Province
1935-1936 Fourth furlough in the USA, then return to Wuhu
1936 Marriage of Ruth Pearce Morgan to Hubert G. Schmidt
1937 -1938 Yangtze River is patrolled by British and American ships -a British ship, shelled by the Japanese, burns and sinks very close to the hospital in Wuhu
1939 RBM spent most of the year in the USA due to ill health, but returned to China in Feb 1940
1939 Marriage of Juliana Louise Morgan to Elmer Wallace Cavins
1941 Spring RBM, due to deteriorating health, returned by ship to the USA and settled in Lansing, IL, with daughter Juliana and her husband Elmer Wallace Cavins
1941 Jul 1 Marriage of Carrel Bennett Morgan and Dorothy Dysart
1941 Dec Japanese took control of the hospital in Wuhu
1942Nov LSM and all staff forced from Wuhu General Hospital and are interned at the Episcopal "True Light" American Church Mission in Wuhu
1943 Jul 14 LSM and companions interned at the Argyle Southern Highlanders (ASH) Camp at the Civil Assembly Center, 63 Great Western Road, Shanghai. RBM did know of his whereabouts until Jan 1944.
1945 Oct LSM and companions returned to the Wuhu General Hospital
1946 Jan Dr. Gilbert Nee arrived at Wuhu Hospital to replace Dr. Morgan
1946 Mar LSM returned to USA
1946 Oct-Nov LSM spent time in recuperation at Clifton Springs Sanitarium, Clifton Springs, NY
1948 The Morgans moved to Packanack Lake, New Jersey, to be close to their son Carrel and his family
1948-1954 LSM worked in New York City with the Associated Medical Missions Office and the National Council of Churches' "Christian Medical Council for Overseas Work"
1955 Mar 9 RBM died of a cerebral aneurysm in Paterson, New Jersey
1955 Jun 10 LSM died of a heart ailment in Wayne, New Jersey
NB: More detailed genealogical information about the Morgan / Bennett families is available in the first folder of Series IV, Biographical Information (Box 24, Folder 349)
Scope and Contents
This collection documents many facets of the life and times of Lorenzo and Ruth Morgan and their three children, both during their time in China as doctors and missionaries (1904-1946) and in the United States (1946-1955) after their return. Extensive correspondence, diaries, writings, biographical data, collected material, and photographs in these archives provide detailed documentation regarding the Morgans' work and the turbulent events of Chinese society during the first half of the twentieth century. These papers complement the papers of Paul and Helen Hayes (YDSL RG18) who were Methodist missionaries stationed in Wuhu and Chinkiang, Anhwei Province from 1921 to 1935.
Series I, Family Correspondence, is the largest portion of the collection. The majority of family correspondence consists of letters of Loren and Ruth to/from their parents and siblings in the U.S. and to their children away at school. The letters describe their six-month journey from Johns Hopkins University in Baltimore to their first assignment in China, as well as the travails and adventures they experienced once they reached their destination. Forty-one years of correspondence from China provides descriptions of the Morgans' medical missionary work, as well as their involvement in various events, including the 1907-1908 famine in Kiang Su [Jiangsu] Province, the 1918 outbreak of plague in Tatung [Datong] and the area northeast of Peking [Beijing], a major revolution against all foreigners in Haichow in 1927; the Japanese invasion of their city, Wuhu, and their hospital in 1936,and the imprisonment of foreigners in Shanghai by the Japanese from 1942 until 1945. The frequent, detailed letters to family members also document family activities, marital stresses, successes and setbacks in their medical work, relationships with other missionaries, daily events including language learning and running a household, trouble with bandits, and so forth. Correspondence between Loren and Ruth during his absence from her while fighting the plague in 1918, and his letters from the internment camp in Shanghai where he was held against his will for over three years (1942-1945) is of particular note. This series also includes correspondence from the three Morgan children to each other, their extended family, and their friends, and letters from other family members to one another.
Series II, General Correspondence, consists of more than 1200 letters arranged in alphabetical order by recipient or sender other than the Morgans. These letters document the Morgans' professional medical and missionary activity. Letters to and from friends, physician colleagues, fellow missionaries, students, benefactors, and various organizations document their personal, collegial and professional relationships. The more prominent correspondents are listed individually and include Ira Cardiff, Ed and Gay Currie, Dr. Ailie Gale, Letty Grafton, Thomas B. Grafton and his son Cornelius, Gilbert Nee, John W. Paxton, Arthur Stillians, the Vinson family, and James Woods. Correspondence with the Mission Boards of the Presbyterian Church in the U.S. and the Methodist Church documents the Morgans' appointment to the mission field and their eventual move from the Presbyterian to the Methodist board.
Series III, Writings, is split into three sub-series: 1) Articles/Reports/Notes; 2) Diaries; 3) Notebooks/Compilations. Writings of Loren Morgan include papers from his high school and college years and his reports to various English edition Chinese newspapers commenting on the political scene and daily vicissitudes of life in China. Also of note are Loren's detailed diaries from the period of his internment at the Argyle Southern Highlanders (ASH) Camp at the Civil Assembly Center,Shanghai. In addition to the fragile originals, there are also photocopies and typed transcripts of the diaries, as well as other related documents, compiled into packets by Carrel Morgan.
Series IV, Biographical Information, consists primarily of printed materials about the five members of the immediate Morgan family and various aspects of their lives. Included in this series would are passports and various academic diplomas of the Morgans, school grades, personal bibles and books used and annotated by them, as well as newspaper and magazine and church bulletin accounts of their various accomplishments and travels and speaking engagements while at home in the U.S. on furlough.
Series V, Collected Material, is divided into five sub-series: 1) Artifacts/memorabilia; 2) Art Work; 3) Publications; 4) Maps of China; 5) Topical Subject Files. While in China, the Morgans took clippings from the English press there and filed them for their own use or sent them home to friends and family members to keep them abreast of developments in China. This part of the collection is valuable because it gives the scholar an on-scene description of events that the Morgans themselves witnessed. These clippings were preserved by family members and in later years were collected by the Morgans' youngest child Carrel to be preserved in this archive. Of particular interest in the "Topical Subject Files" are materials related to Ellen Lavine Graham Hospital, Haichow, the Wuhu General Hospital, the plague in Tatung (1918), the murder by bandits of John W. Vinson, and materials related to former students and aides in China whom the Morgans sponsored for medical training and practice in the USA.
Series VI, Photographs, is divided into four sub-series: 1) People; 2) Places; 3) Topics; and 4) Scrapbooks/compilations. The people depicted are primarily the Morgan family, Western missionary colleagues, and Chinese people, including during the famine years of 1906-1907. Places depicted include the hospitals where the Morgans worked and the Haichow, Kuling, and Wuhu areas. Topical groupings include photos related to the ASH internment camp, the German airplane that landed in Haichow in 1914, and the trip of Carrel and Dorothy Morgan to China in 2000 to participate in ceremonies there honoring the work of Loren and Ruth Morgan. The scrapbook collections of photographs were primarily compiled by Carrel Morgan and document various aspects of the Morgans' life and work in China.
Arrangement
I. Family Correspondence, 1862-2001
II. General Correspondence, 1900-1990
III. Writings, 1895-2001
IV. Biographical Information, 1868-1955
V. Collected Material, 1900-1994
VI. Photographs, 1885-2000
Missions -- China; Missions, Medical -- China; Missionaries; Morgan, Lorenzo Seymour; Morgan, Ruth Bennett
- Family Correspondence, 1862-2001; Series I
  - Ruth Bennett to/from mother and aunt
    - Incl. from Y.W.C.A summer camp in Lake Geneva IL, 1897 Oct - 1898 Aug (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Incl. re. life in Baltimore, MD while attending Johns Hopkins Medical School, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Incl. from Baltimore and from Schenectady NY and East Northfield MA during summer, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 5)
    - From Baltimore, 1901 Jan - Mar (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - From Baltimore and Y.W.C.A. summer camp, Williams Bay, 1901 Apr- Jul (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ruth, brother Ralph, and aunt in Berkeley CA, 1901 Nov - Dec (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ruth, brother Ralph, and aunt in San Francisco CA, 1902 Jan - Mar (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Return to Baltimore, 1902 Sep - Dec (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Incl. to Ralph as well as mother and aunt, from Baltimore, 1903 Jan - Mar (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - From Baltimore and Gananoque, Ontario, Canada, 1903 Apr - Jun (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - From Ontario, 1903 Jul (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - From Ontario; return to Baltimore. Marriage proposal from Loren Morgan, 1903 Aug - Sep (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - From Baltimore, 1903 Oct - Dec (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - From Baltimore, 1904 Jan - Mar (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - From Baltimore, 1904 Apr - May (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Graduation from Johns Hopkins; choice of Southern Presbyterian Mission Board vs. Northern Board, 1904 Jan - Jun (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ruth Bennett to/from brother Ralph
    - Ruth in Baltimore; Ralph in Schenectady NY, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 19 -20)
    - Ruth in Baltimore and East Northfield; Ralph in Schenectady, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 21 - 23)
    - Ruth in Baltimore; Ralph in Schenectady, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Ruth in Baltimore; Ralph in Los Angeles (1904), 1902 - 1904 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Lorenzo Morgan (LSM) to/from Mary Bennett
    - Letters of LSM to Ruth's mother prior to marriage, 1903 Dec - 1904 Mar (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - LSM and RBM to/from family in U.S.
    - Bound volume of letters to family of LSM; re. visit to Presbyterian Board in Nashville; marriage; travel to CA en route to China, 1904 Jun - Nov (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - From Nashville; Galva IL; re. marriage, 1904 Jun - Jul (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - From Galva and en route to CA, 1904 Aug - Sep (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - En route to China, 1904 Oct - Nov (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Stop in Japan; arrival in Shanghai; to Tsing Kiang Pu, 1904 Dec (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Based at the hospital in Tsing Kiang Pu [Qingjiang], Kiang Su [Jiangsu] Province; incl. hand drawn map of area; re. learning Chinese, 1905 Jan (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. Chinese New Year celebrations, 1905 Feb (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl re. Chinese women, kites; missionaries' children event, 1905 Mar (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. beginning medical work, 1905 Apr (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. medical cases, unbinding of woman's feet, 1905 May (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; increased medical work due to illness of Dr. Wood, 1905 Jun (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - At Kuling mountain resort, 1905 Jul (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Kuling; incl. program of concert, re. meeting of North Kiang Su Mission of Southern Presbyterian Board, 1905 Aug (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Kuling; incl. re. food, activities, 1905 Sep (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - From Kuling to Shanghai, 1905 Oct (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Visit in Shanghai; return to Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. drawing showing layout of their house, 1905 Nov (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. Chinese weddings, 1905 Dec (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Undated letters, ca. 1905 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl.layout of house, re. training servants, medical work, language work, 1906 Jan (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. Chinese New Year; incl. re. reports of anti-foreign movement, 1906 Feb (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. fire in town, 1906 Mar (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; RBM miscarriage; LSM away itinerating to Haichow, 1906 Apr - May (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - LSM in Tsing Kiang Pu; RBM in Kuling, 1906 Jun - Jul (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Kuling and return to Tsing Kiang Pu, 1906 Aug - Sep (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. famine refugees, 1906 Oct - Nov (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. famine; drawings of house layout and area, 1906 Dec (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. famine, 1907 Jan - Feb (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. death of infant son, 1907 Mar - Apr (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re famine, 1907 May - Jun (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Trip to Hong Kong; then Kuling, 1907 Jul -Aug (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Kuling; incl. plan for house, then return to Tsing Kiang Pu, 1907 Sep - Oct (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; LSM travels to cover for ill doctor, 1907 Nov - Dec (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; incl. re. birth of Ruth Pearce Morgan, thoughts of RBM re. role of missionary wives, 1908 Jan - Jun (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - RBM to Kuling with RPM; LSM visits Shanghai then return to Tsing Kiang Pu, 1908 Jul - Sep (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Kuling; return to Tsing Kiang Pu, 1908 Oct - Dec (Box 4, Folder 60a)
    - Tsing Kiang Pu; trip to Suchien; RBM medical work; LSM to Haichow, 1909 Jan - Jun (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Kuling, 1909 Jul - Sep (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Kuling then removal to Haichow station American Presbyterian Church, South, North Kiangsu Mission, 1909 Oct - Dec (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Based in Haichow [Haizhou], Kiang Su [Jiangsu] Province, 1910 Jan - Mar (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Haichow; work at dispensary, 1910 Apr - Jun (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Haichow; then at "Temple by the Sea", 1910 Jul -Aug (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Haichow; work at dispensary; trip to Shanghai, 1910 Sep- Oct (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Haichow; incl. re. Sunday church service, 1910 Nov - Dec (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Haichow; RBM in need of surgery, 1911 Jan - Feb (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Haichow; move to new house, 1911 Mar - Apr (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Furlough in U.S., 1911 May - Nov (Box 5, Folder 71 - 72)
    - Return to Haichow/ Tunghaihsien, 1912 Oct - Dec (Box 5, Folder 73 - 75)
    - Haichow, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 76 - 79)
    - Haichow; birth of Juliana in Tsingtao, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 80 - 82)
    - Haichow / seaside; trip to mission meeting in Kuling, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 83 - 87)
    - Haichow / Kuling resort, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 88 - 89)
    - Haichow; birth of Carrel Bennett Morgan, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 90 - 91)
    - LSM involved in plague prevention in Tatung [Datong] in northeast China, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 92 - 94)
    - Haichow, 1919 Jan - Apr (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Haichow to furlough in U.S., 1919 May - Dec (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Furlough in U.S., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 97 - 100)
    - Furlough in U.S.; return to Haichow, Ellen Lavine Graham Hospital, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 101 - 102)
    - Haichow / Kuling resort, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Haichow, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Haichow, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Haichow / seaside resort, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 106 - 107)
    - Haichow / seaside resort, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 108 - 109)
    - Haichow / furlough in U.S., 1927 (Box 7, Folder 110 - 111)
    - Furlough in U.S., 1928 (Box 7, Folder 112 - 115)
    - Haichow, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 116 - 117)
    - Haichow, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 118 - 119)
    - Haichow; murder of John Vinson by bandits, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 120)
    - Haichow; family financial difficulties due to Depression, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Based at Presbyterian hospital, Chinkiang; RBM working with Chinese women with venereal diseases, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - Transfer to Methodist Hospital in "Ichisan," Wuhu, Anhwei [Anhui] Province, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - Wuhu / Furlough in U.S., 1935 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Furlough in U.S.; return to Wuhu, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - Wuhu, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 126)
    - Wuhu, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 127 - 128)
    - RBM in U.S. due to ill health, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 129 - 130)
    - RBM returns to China, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - RBM returns to U.S.; Japanese take control of the hospital in Wuhu in December, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 132)
    - Nov. - LSM interned at the Episcopal "True Light" American Church Mission in Wuhu, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 133)
    - LSM interned at the Argyle Southern Highlanders (ASH) Camp at the Civil Assembly Center, Shanghai, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 134)
    - LSM internment continues through Jan., 1944 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    - LSM returns to Wuhu hospital, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 136 - 137)
    - LSM returns to U.S., 1946 (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - RBM and LSM based in Lansing, IL; LSM recuperating at sanitarium in Clifton Springs, NY, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 139)
    - RBM and LSM based in NJ, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 140)
    - NJ, 1949-1954 (Box 9, Folder 141-146)
    - NJ; death of RBM, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - Fragments, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 148)
  - RBM / LSM to/from each other
    - Incl. LSM doing plague work in Tatung (see also compiled packets of documentation in Collected Material, Box 33), 1909-1918 (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - On furlough in U.S., 1920 Apr - Dec (Box 9, Folder 149a-150)
    - Incl. LSM visiting children in Shanghai, 1921, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 151)
    - Various, 1928 May - Dec (Box 9, Folder 152-153)
    - LSM in Haichow; RBM in Tsingtao, 1930 - 1932 (Box 10, Folder 154)
    - Various, 1933 - 1940 (Box 10, Folder 155-156)
    - RBM in US; LSM in China, 1941 - 1944 (Box 10, Folder 157)
    - RBM in US to LSM in internment in China, 1945 May - Oct (Box 10, Folder 158)
    - RBM in US; LSM in China, 1945 Nov - Dec (Box 10, Folder 159)
    - RBM in US; LSM in China, 1946 Jan - Mar (Box 10, Folder 160)
    - LSM returns from China; at Clifton Springs Sanitarium, Clifton Springs, NY, 1946 Aug - Nov (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Various, 1949 - 1954 (Box 10, Folder 161a)
  - LSM/RBM to/from their children
    - Incl. to RPM from LSM in Tatung while was doing plague work, 1918 Mar - 1922 Sep (Box 10, Folder 162)
    - To RPM, 1922 Oct - 1923 (Box 10, Folder 163)
    - Primarily to RPM, incl. at Shanghai American School, 1924 - 1927 (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - To/from RPM, JLM, CBM, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 165)
    - Primarily to/from RPM, CBM, 1929 - 1930 Jul (Box 10, Folder 166)
    - Incl. re. tensions between LSM and RBM, 1930 Aug - Dec (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - Primarily to/from RPM, CBM, 1931 Jan - Jun (Box 10, Folder 168)
    - Primarily to/from RPM, CBM, 1931 Jul - Dec (Box 10, Folder 169)
    - Primarily to/from CBM, 1932 Jan - Mar (Box 10, Folder 170)
    - Primarily to/from CBM; to RPM from LSM re. tensions with RBM (living apart), 1932 Apr - May (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - Incl. re. JLM trip from China to U.S., 1932 Jun - Dec (Box 10, Folder 172)
    - Primarily to/from CBM at Shanghai American School, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 173)
    - Primarily to/from CBM at Shanghai American School and RPM, 1934 Jan - Jun (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - To/from RPM and JLM in U.S./ CBM in Shanghai, 1934 Jul - Dec (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Inc. re. murder of Stams, 1935 Jan - Jun (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Incl. from LSM en route to U.S. through Middle East and Europe, 1935 Jul - Sep (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Primarily from RPM, 1935 Oct - Dec (Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Incl. from CBM at SAS, 1936 Jan - Mar (Box 11, Folder 179)